<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Avery&#39;s Data Blog</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Avery&#39;s Data Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Computer Vision: Image Segmentation for Improved Scene Classification</title>
      <link>/2021/09/14/computer-vision/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/09/14/computer-vision/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to Matthew Kaplan, my brilliant and dedicated project partner.
For Stanford’s class CS231N: Convolutional Neural Networks for Visual Recognition, my partner Matthew and I decided to work on scene classification: how might a computer tell the difference between a beach, a city street, and a mountain range at sunset? Scenes are more difficult to classify than objects because of their complexity and the huge variance between images of the same scene type.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Bitcoin</title>
      <link>/2021/09/11/exploring-bitcoin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/09/11/exploring-bitcoin/</guid>
      <description>*Code can be found on Github right here.
I will admit that I’m historically something of a crypto skeptic - blame a mix of risk aversion and Silicon Valley’s grandiose delusions. But as passes its 12th anniversary, I have come to accept that crypto is here to stay. As a result, I figured I might as well understand its meteoric rise and figure out where it’s headed.
First, I look at Bitcoin’s rise, along with the rise in miner revenue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Face Recognition and Single Value Decomposition (SVD)</title>
      <link>/2021/05/23/face-recognition-and-svd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/05/23/face-recognition-and-svd/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR I use Single Value Decomposition (SVD) to approximate photos of my own face and check if Apple’s Photos app can still recognize my face at low rank levels. I find that the Photo app can recognize my face at rank 25, a 98% decrease in storage size from the original image. I hypothesize that SVD works particularly well on faces because of facial symmetry.
*Code for this project can be found on Github right here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Happiness EDA</title>
      <link>/2021/03/26/world-happiness-eda/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/03/26/world-happiness-eda/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR According to data from the 2021 World Happiness Report, wealth, social support, and life expectancy all seem to correlate strongly with happiness across countries. Perceptions of corruption appears to correlate negatively with happiness, though outliers exist. Generosity does not seem to correlate with happiness at all, though the proxy for generosity (donating to a charity within the last month) seems ill-adapted to capture the kinds of informal help offered between members of distinct communities that dominate poorer and politically fragile countries.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>